I wish they had something smaller.
もっと小振りなのがいいんだよな
Hey, Lord Hak, what are you doing here in the middle of the night?
ハク様 何やってんのこんな夜中に
悪いおやじ  起こしちまったか
Sorry. Did I wake you?
No, that's not what I meant.
いや そうじゃなくて
The door is broken.
戸 壊れてるし
I want a small sword and bow.
小降りの剣と弓が欲しい
Are you going hunting?
狩りにでも行かれるんで
Yeah.
そうだな
I'm going away.
行ってくる
長旅になるかもしれないが
I may be gone for a while.
Sorry to bother you.
邪魔したな
L-Lord Hak, you're paying for these?
ハ ハク様がお代を...
You always say to put it on your tab.
いつもは付けとけ とか言うのに
Thanks for everything.
おやじ 世話になったな
Live a long life.
長生きしろよ
You're so serious now,
なんか しんみりしてきたぞ
you dumb Thunder Beast.
バカ雷獣
Episode 5:   Howl
He's back! Hean-dea's back!
戻ったぞ ヘンデが戻ってきた
テヨン 大丈夫
Tae-yeon, are you feeling better?
神業的速さだな ヘンデ
That was inhumanly fast, Hean-dea.
ヘンデにお任せ
Leave it to me...
苦しくない 欲しい物はある
Are you in pain? Is there anything you need?
Thank you. I'm fine.
ありがとう 俺元気だよ
Twinge
What an adorable creature!
可愛い
Let me nuzzle you!
抱きさせて
Let me hold you!
Hean-dea, live.
ヘンデ 生きろ
All right. I'm going to check on the merchants.
よし 俺は商団の見舞いに行ってくるわ
ついでにこの屍葬ってくる
I'll also bury this corpse while I'm at it.
But I'm alive, I think...
生きてるつもり...
はい 退いた退いた
Move, move.
は リナちゃん
Oh, Rina!
おばあ様
Ma'am?
あら嫌だ お ば あ さ まっだ何て
Oh, my. Did you call me "ma'am"?
Elegant...
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
Perfect timing. Take these.
ちょうど良かった これ運んでくれ
Really, those Fire Tribe men are out of control.
まったく 火の部族の奴らめちゃくちゃやるんだから
中はけが人だらけだよ
Lots of injured people in there.
火の部族に襲われた商団の人達
The merchants that were attacked by the Fire Tribe...
Why did this happen?
どうしてこんな事に
What have we done to deserve this?
私らが何をしたって言うんだい
As long as you're alive, things will work out.
生きてりゃ何とでもなるっさ
いざとなったらあたしが世話してやるから
If it comes to it, I'll take care of you.
Whoops.
ごめんリナさん ふらついちゃって
Sorry, Rina. I'm a little unsteady.
Rina?
リナさん
The Fire Tribe would go this far
to put Su-won on the throne?
火の部族はスウォンを即位させる為にここまでするの
This absurdity is permissible?
こんな不条理が許されるの
Can you...
あなたは あなたは許せるの スウォン
Can you allow this, Su-won?
It's all right!
大丈夫
We'll be fine with the young lord
and the elder around.
若長や長老が居る限りね
Despite how they seem,
they look out for their family.
あの人達 ああ見えて家族思いだから
Family...
家族...
Yeah! Everyone in the Wind Tribe is family.
そう 風の部族の皆は家族なのです
So you're part of our family now too.
だからリナさんも もう俺らの家族なのです
Huh?
泣かせたな ヘンデ
Aw, you made her cry, Hean-dea.
ハク様に殺される
Lord Hak's gonna kill me!
ハクやムンドク 優しい風の部族の人達
Hak and Mun-deok. The kind people of the Wind Tribe.
They must be feeling such terrible pain and intense rage.
強い痛みもあるだろ 激しい怒りもあるだろ
胸に締まって笑う 誇り高い風
The proud wind hides these feelings within and smiles.
Huh?
Rina, are you all right?
リナさん 大丈夫
I can't let these people get caught up in this.
この人達を巻き込んではダメ
ハク
Hak...
テヨン
Tae-yeon?
リナ
Rina...
今のは ハク
Was that Hak?
Yeah.
リナはどうしたの
What is it, Rina?
I wanted to thank you.
お礼を言いたいの
Thank me?
お礼？
You gave me good food, wiped away my tears, and cheered me up.
あったかいご飯をくれて涙を拭ってくれて元気くれて
ありがとう
Thank you.
お世話になりました
Thank you for everything.
I thought you were going to stay here forever.
リナはずっとここに居るんだと思ってた
なんだ
Oh, well...
死にたいと思った夜もあったけど
Some nights, I wanted to die.
この小さな体で
But with this small body,
苦しさなんか微塵も感じさせない笑顔と強さが
with his strength and smiles that never showed the slightest sign of pain,
私に勇気をくれたの
he gave me courage.
私 忘れない テヨンとここの人達を
I won't forget you or the people who live here.
Stay well, and take care.
体を大切に 元気で
ごめんなさい ハク兄ちゃん
I'm sorry, Hak.
リナを守るって約束したばかりなのに
I just promised I would protect Rina...
守れそうにないや
but I don't think I'll be able to.
今日はまともに門番してるみたいだな
Looks like you're actually keeping watch today.
背中を預ける奴が居ないと眠れねぇんで
I can't sleep without someone at my back.
寝るな
Don't sleep.
Where are you going, Lord Hak?
ハク様はどちらへ
I'm leaving.
俺 ここを出るわ
Really? See you later.
あぁ いってらっしゃい
Seriously?
マジで
That means you're the Wind Tribe's next chief.
つぅ訳で 次期風の部族長はお前な
No way! It's too much work!
嫌だよ面倒くさい
Wait, are you leaving Rina behind?
て言うか リナさんを置いてつもり
I thought about seeing her before I left, but...
最後くらい 顔を見ようかと思ったけどな
あいつも纏めて頼むわ
Take care of her too.
Princesses with baggage are a heavy burden.
訳ありのお姫様何て 荷が重いっすよ
You knew?
お前 気づいて...
Hak!
ハク
I'm leaving this place.
私 ここを出る
Come with me!
一緒に来なさい
なんだって
What did you say?
ここを出るの
I'm leaving.
ここに居たら風牙の都を争いに巻き込んでしまう
If I stay here, Capital Fuuga will
be caught up in the conflict.
帰れ
Go back.
I've already spoken to the elder.
長老にはその旨 伝えてある
もうここは大丈夫だ
This place is safe now.
You should live here quietly.
あんたはここで静かに暮らせ
お前が一人で行くの 許した覚えはないわ
I don't remember allowing you to leave alone.
You told me to use you as a tool to live.
私が生きる為に自分を使えとハクは言ってくれたじゃない
I've returned the name of "Son."
俺はソンの名を返した
I'm no longer a general or your servant.
もう将軍でもなければあんたの従者でもない
I'm about to leave on a free journey.
これから自由の旅に出ようってのに
I don't have to take care of you.
あんたの面倒まで見る義理ねぇな
If you keep quiet, Su-won won't do anything.
あんたが静かにしてればスウォンも手出しはしない
Move.
退け
I've already decided!
もう決めたの
No matter what you think,
I'm not taking you with me.
どう思おうが俺は連れて行かない
金はあるのか
Do you have money?
If we're going to be traveling together, I'll have to protect you.
これから先 一緒に行くなら
どうしたって俺はあんたを守らなきゃならない
I'm asking if you have the money
to pay for my services.
今のあんたに俺の働きに見合う金を払う事が出来るかって聞いてんだよ
Or will you pay with your body?
それとも 体で払うか
I don't have anything to give you.
あげられる物何て 何もないわ
You catch on quick.
物分りがいいな
Now, go.
さ 戻れ
Goodbye, Princess Yona.
さよなら ヨナ姫
But I want you!
でも お前が欲しいもの
Give yourself to me, Hak!
私にハクを頂戴
なんだ そりゃ
What are you talking about?
やっぱ すげぇ我がまま
You're so willful.
あぁくそぉむかつく
Damn it. It's so annoying.
これだから
This is why...
You win, Princess.
あんたの勝ちです 姫様
Hak...
ハク
Old man!
Call me "Grandpa"!
爺さんと呼べ
Were you there the whole time?
ずっとそこに
I heard you being rude to the princess!
さっきから聞いていれば姫様に対する暴言の数々
Mun-deok...
ムンドク
It seems I must let another grandchild go.
孫をまた一人 手放すようじゃ
Everyone told me...
私 皆にも言われたの
that I was family.
家族だって
It made me happy.
嬉しかった
だから出ていくの
That's why I'm leaving.
Mun-deok, please protect the Wind Tribe.
ムンドク どうか風の部族を守って
Don't forget, Princess.
忘れないでくだされ 姫様
いつかあなたが再び絶望に立たされ 助けを求めた時
If you ever lose hope again and need assistance,
我ら風の部族は誰を敵に回してもお味方致します
the Wind Tribe will always be by your side, no matter who stands against us,
どんなに遠く離れても
nor how far away you may be.
Lord Kang Tae-jun.
カンテジュン様
後にしろ しょんぼり中だ
Tell me later. I'm miserable.
はい
What?
My father scolded me.
父上に怒られたのだ
勝手に行動するなと
He told me not to act without permission.
そんなテジュン様に朗報ですよ
I have good news for you, Lord Tae-jun.
Huh?
風牙の都付近でヨナ姫を見たとの情報が
Princess Yona was spotted near Capital Fuuga.
なに
What?
赤い髪の少女を兵が確認しました
A soldier saw a girl with red hair.
側にはハク将軍も居て二人はその後北山の方へ向かったとか
General Hak was also with her.
The two of them were heading toward the northern mountains.
北山だと
The northern mountains?
あの様ななにもない所へ なぜ
Why would they go to such a desolate place?
Who knows?
あの男も一緒なのだな
So that man is with her, then?
巡ってきた
My luck has turned.
兵を集めろ
Gather the soldiers!
ヨナ姫を捉えるぞ
We'll capture Princess Yona!
何か見えた
Do you see anything?
皆無
No.
あのじじ
How does the old man expect us to find someone, when we don't know where he is?
何処に居るのか分からん奴を探せっつってもな
神官？
A priest?
そう
Yes.
古より
Since ancient times, a priest who has seen the Kingdom of Kouka's future
この高華国の未来を見据えてきた神官様が
風の地のどこかにおられると言う
has been said to live somewhere
within the Wind Tribe's territory.
If you're not certain what to do next, you should seek out the priest.
姫様がこれからどうすべきかを迷っておられるなら
神官様のもとへ行きなされ
I'm sure he will show you the way.
きっと道を示して下さる
Long ago, the priest lived in
a temple at the royal palace
昔から 神官は王宮の神殿に住まい
国の政に大きく関わっていたと聞く
and was deeply involved in the kingdom's governance.
ユホン様が神官を弾圧してからは
After Yu-hon began oppressing the priest, he left the castle.
城を出て今は人里離れた場所にひっそりと暮らしているんだと
Now he lives quietly, somewhere far from people.
Far from people.
人里を離れた
This certainly doesn't seem like somewhere a person could live.
確かに誰も住めそうにない場所
If you tried living here, you might fall off a cliff.
まぁ 姫さんが住んだら
即 崖から転がり落ちるかもしれんが
But I'm sure a person could do it if he really tried.
その気になりゃ 何とか住めるだろう
Even though I called myself the princess of the kingdom, I only knew Hiryuu Castle.
私はこの国の姫を名乗っていたのに
知っているのは緋龍城だけ
It sounds foolish to say I don't know.
知らない 何て愚かな響き
What path should I follow now?
私の行くべき道か
今は生きるだけで精一杯だ
At this moment, just trying to live
is taking everything I have.
By the way, Princess,
ところでお姫様
if we must search every corner of this area,
we'll have to sleep outside.
この辺を虱潰しに探すとなると野宿になるが どうします
What should we do?
Sleep outside? I've gotten a bit used to it.
野宿 少しは慣れたわ
Unlike the mountains behind the castle,
it gets cold here.
城の裏山と違ってここは冷えますよ
Then I'll snuggle against you while I sleep.
その時はハクに包まって寝るから
Whoosh
Jeez...
ったく
I don't mind,
いいけど
but I'll play pranks on you.
いたずらしますよ
Pranks?
いたずら
Pranks are...
いたずらって言うのは
things like this.
こう言う事とか
ハク ちょっと なにすっ...
Hak, what are you-
静かに
Quiet.
Footsteps.
四十...いや 五十か
Forty. No, fifty.
Pursuers?
追手
I thought they weren't chasing us anymore.
もう追う気がねぇのかと思ってたけど
That's quite a lot of people too.
こりゃまた気合の入った数だな
Are they the king's men?
王の兵
Or-
それとも
Princess,
姫様
やっぱ包まって寝るんなら もうちょい抱き心地よくねと
if we're going to be snuggling in our sleep,
I won't feel like playing pranks on you
if you're not a bit more comfortable to hold.
もうちょい抱き心地よくねと
いたずらする気も起きないですよ
なんの話だ なんの
What are you talking about?
Zoom
さてと
Now, then.
準備運動もしましたし
I'm all warmed up.
Time to get to work.
働きましょうか
離れないで下さいよ お姫様
Stay close, Princess.
He truly is a Thunder Beast.
まさに雷獣
スウォンがいつか言っていた
Su-won once said...
Hak's techniques are like lightning.
ハクの技は稲妻みたいなんです
If we fought in earnest, I'm sure he would destroy me.
本気で戦えば 私はきっとコテンコテンですよ
Even in these moments,
I still remember your face so naturally.
こんな時に まだあ素直にあなたの顔を思い出す
どうした
What's wrong?
これで終わりか
Are you finished?
雷獣は健在だな
I see the Thunder Beast is going strong.
やっぱりあんたか
So it is you.
この時を待ちわびていましたよ
I've been waiting for this moment,
ソンハク将軍
General Son Hak...
そしてヨナ姫
and Princess Yona.
火の部族 このカンテジュンが...
I, Kang Tae-jun, of the Fire Tribe...
見てください姫様 自然がいっぱいだ
Look, Princess. There's nature everywhere.
What?!
Why are you enjoying nature
while I'm talking to you?
なぜ私が話しかけてる最中に自然を満喫するのだ
Oh, you were talking to me?
おう なんだ 俺に話しかけてたのか
I'm neither a general nor a "Son" now.
俺は今将軍でもソンでもないんで
Sorry about that.
すみませんね どうも
It's fine, as long as you understand.
あいや そんな 分かって貰えばよいのだ
Wait, what? You're not a general?
って何 将軍ではない
That's right. I'm just wandering traveler Hak.
ですよ 俺はただの流離の旅人ハク
That means...
つぅ訳で
whatever I do now has nothing
to do with the Wind Tribe.
俺がこれから何をしても
風の部族はなんら関係ございませんので
So that's it.
そう言う事か
Well, either way, I don't care about the Wind Tribe.
でもまぁ風の部族はどうでもよい
邪魔者は消えて貰うのみ
I will make those who stand in my way disappear.
I have business with Princess Yona!
そこに居るヨナ姫に用があるのでな
休む間を与えるな
Don't let him rest!
止めろ 奴を止めろ
Stop him! Stop him!
Archers, fire!
矢を放て
姫さん 太ったな
You've gained weight, Princess.
一言多い
That was unnecessary!
走るぞ
We're gonna run.
After them!
I'm scared. There are arrows and
soldiers closing in from all sides.
怖い 四方から矢と兵が押し寄せて
Not even Hak can handle all of these.
いくらハクでもこんなに
姫を狙え
Aim for the princess!
ハク
Hak!
Hak, are you all right?
ハク 大丈夫
Hak...
ハク
Don't worry about me. It's creepy.
心配なんてしないでくださいよ 気持ち悪い
Why, you-
お前は...
すげぇ
Amazing.
Don't stand around impressed!
感心するな
He's injured! After him!
奴は手負いだ 追え
We haven't found them yet.
まだ見つてません
What about over there?
そっちはどうだ
いない
They're not here!
Don't move, no matter what.
絶対に動かないでくださいよ
Hak, you're bleeding.
ハク お前 血が...
It isn't mine.
返り血ですよ
But...
そんな 待って ハク
Wait, Hak.
If we're going to be traveling together,
I'll have to protect you.
一緒に行くなら どうしたっても
俺はあんたを守らなきゃならない
私を庇って...
To protect me, you...
Where's the princess? Where did Princess Yona disappear to?
姫は ヨナ姫どこに消えたのだ
Kang Tae-jun...
カンテジュン
Hak apparently helped her escape.
ハクがどこかに逃がしたようですね
Find her!
必ず見つけ出せ
The Thunder Beast is human too.
雷獣も人の子よ
He seems to be tiring.
さすがに疲れが見えてきた様だな
先程当てた矢は毒矢です
The arrow that hit him was poisoned.
何 それを姫に向けたのか
What?
You fired poisoned arrows at the princess?
I knew Hak would shield the princess with his body if we fired at her.
向ければハクは体を張ってでも
矢を止めると確信がありましたから
An ordinary person wouldn't be able to move.
常人であればまず動けません
恐ろしい男です
He's a terrifying man.
ならば 次に背中を向けた時を狙え
Then when he turns his back, fire at him.
ハクが殺される
They're going to kill Hak?
絶対に動かないで下さいよ
Don't move, no matter what.
That's right.
そうだ
私が出て行っても 反って足を引っ張る
If I reveal myself, I'll only slow him down.
大丈夫よ
It'll be fine.
Hak is so strong.
ハクはあんなに強いんだもの
ハクなら...ハクなら矢くらい避けられる
Hak... Hak can dodge an arrow.
ここで大人しくしてハクが来るのを待とう
I should quietly wait here for Hak to come.
ハクは死んだりなんか...
Hak won't die.
No. Why did I leave Capital Fuuga?
違う 私は何のために風牙の都を出たの
So I could live in hiding, under Hak's protection?
ハクに守られてこそこそ生きるため？
If that's the case, I should've stayed in Capital Fuuga.
それなら風牙の都に居ればよかったんだ
I'm just a burden to Hak.
これではハクの足枷になるだけ
I'm sure the priest will show you the way.
神官様がこれからの道をきっと示して下さる
Before I question the gods,
神に問う前に 自分に問う事があるはずよ
there are questions I should ask myself!
ヨ...ナ
Yona...
Wh-What is this?
なんだ
ヨナ姫
Princess Yona...
I never thought you'd come to me yourself.
まさか そちらから来られるとは
お話をしたいと思っていたのですよ
I wanted to speak to you.
There's no need to be so cautious.
そんなに警戒しないで
I came to get you.
私はあなたをお迎えに来たのです
迎え？
Get me?
Tomorrow morning, Lord Su-won will be crowned as the new king.
明朝 スウォン様が新王に即位されます
Poor princess...
お可哀想に 姫様
It must have been painful, losing the king and being chased from the castle.
陛下をなくされ 城を追われるなど身を切られる思いでしょう
Come with me, and we'll make this known.
私と来て この件を公表すれば
あなたを追い出した憎きスウォンを玉座から引きずり降ろし
We can drag the detestable Su-won, who chased you from the castle,
陛下の敵を討つ事が出来ます
off the throne and avenge the king.
なぜ動いた
Why did you move?
ですから姫 私と...
So, Princess, come with me-
そこまで知っていて なぜ風の部族に圧力をかけたの
If you knew that, why did the Fire Tribe put pressure on the Wind Tribe?
Huh?
いや あれは父上の指示で私の意志では...
Those were my father's orders.
It wasn't my idea.
なぜ商団まで襲ったの
Why did you attack the merchants?
真実を知っているのなら
If you know the truth, then instead of driving the Wind Tribe into a corner,
風の部族を追い詰める前に 罪のないハクを殺す前に
instead of trying to kill the innocent Hak,
お前のすべき事があるはずだ
there's something else you should be doing!
燃える様な瞳
Those burning eyes.
なぜだ 目が逸らせない
Why? I can't look away.
私は何も知らない姫だが
I may be an ignorant princess,
but I'm not desperate enough to listen to someone who doesn't understand reason!
道理も分からぬ者の言葉に耳を貸す程 落ちぶれではいない
姫
Princess!
The red hair of what should have
been the young, weak princess...
幼くて弱いはずの姫の赤い髪が己を焼き尽くす炎に見えた
appeared to be a flame consuming her.
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
次回 暁のヨナ 第六話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 6:
Episode 6:   Red Hair
赤い髪
Red Hair.